I was always wondering...
我常常幻想
what my future would be like.
長大後的我會是怎樣的
Good morning, Truly.
真心姐早
Morning.
早
Graduate from my dream school,
從理想的學校畢業
fully develop my potential,
發揮才華
realize my dreams.
實現夢想
Bravo!
BRAVO
The lucrative deal in Shenzhen
深圳的大單
is finally signed to us.
終於簽約成功
Listen,
來
you should learn more from Truly.
要多多向林真心學習
Do everything you can for the company.
替公司賣命
Fight for more good deals!
爭取更多的好業績
Cheers!
Cheers
Thank you boss.
謝謝老闆
Thank you.
謝謝  · · ·
Wow!
哎
What is this, Truly?
真心姐這什麼
So shiny!
好閃哦
Congratulations!
恭喜姐
Double good news!
雙喜臨門哪
And have a perfect relationship.
然後遇到一份完美的愛情
My life will shine...
我的人生會像鑽石一樣
like a diamond.
閃閃發亮
Hsin, go tell her.
小欣 你去說啦
We've worked over time for so many days...
都連續加班好幾天了
Truly.
真心姐
Can we go now?
我們可以下班了嗎
Sure, bye bye!
可以  · · ·再見
Bye bye.
再見
- See you tomorrow. - Bye bye.
- 明天見 辛苦了啊 - 再見
Thank you, Truly!
謝謝真心姐
Hurray!
喔 太好羅
Shall we got for spicy hot pot?
我們去吃麻辣鍋好不好
Sure.
好呀
Which restaurant? I'll make a reservation.
想吃哪一家 我先訂
Hello?
喂
What time do you think it is?
都幾點了
Why are you still in the office?
你怎麼還會在公司
I've been waiting for 5 minutes.
我已經等了你五分鐘了
Sorry.
對不起
I'll go to the restaurant now.
我現在立刻趕過去
If you're not here in 5 minutes, I'll leave.
五分鐘不到我就走人
That's not enough time!
五分鐘怎麼來得及
It'll take me half an hour to get there.
我過去餐廳都要半個小時
Hello?
喂  · · ·
Shit.
死定了
Conference call with Edinburgh at midnight.
半夜愛丁堡那邊要視訊會議
Your team will stay to prepare for it.
你們這一組留下來準備
But I have...
可是我晚上  · · ·
I'll do it now.
我立刻就去準備
Look at Truly.
學學你們真心姐
What a role model!
優秀
Yes, sir.
是
Everyone.
大家
Let's stay a little longer to work on it.
再留晚一點準備一下開會資料
Go! Go! Go!
加油
Earlier done, earlier home.
早點作完早點回家
No one ever told me,
從來沒有人告訴我
the truth is... when you grow up,
原來長大以後
it's likely you'll have a not-so-good job,
你可能只會做一份不怎麼樣的工作
be in a not-so-good relationship,
談一場不怎麼樣的感情
and live a not-so-good life.
將就着過一段不怎麼樣的生活
Dunno what he wants to eat.
不知道喜歡吃什麼
It seems like Hsin is on a diet...
小欣好像在減肥
Go! Go! Go! Early done, early home.
加油！早點作完早點回家喔
She's the one who told us to stay.
就是她叫我們加班的啊
I won't get her bonus anyway.
業績獎金也沒有我的份
The manager told us to learn from Truly.
早上有沒有聽到經理說要跟真心一樣
Fuck! Who wants to learn from her?
靠夭！誰要跟她一樣啊
Working overtime for little salary.
工作超時 薪水又不夠用
She treats the company as her family.
她把公司當家人
The company treats her as animal.
公司把她當畜牲
To be honest,
其實我覺得她這種人
I feel bad for people like her.
也是滿可憐的啦
I hope I won't be like her when I get old.
希望我老了以後不會跟她一樣
Who wants to be like her! Miserable.
誰要跟她一樣啊 那不就很衰
I think...
我想
if I ran into this woman
十八歲的我
when I was 18,
如果在街上偶然遇到這個女人
I would have definitely laughed at her
一定也會和他們一樣
like them, without mercy.
毫不留情的嘲笑她
Yabiyabi. Good evening everyone.
呀比  · · ·晚安 各位
This is Guangyu.
我是光禹
Do you like who you are now?
你喜歡現在的自己嗎
When we grow up,
長大之後的我們
we become sophisticated and tend to compromise
爲了生存 會變得世故
in order to survive.
容易妥協
We become someone we don't recognize.
甚至變得都不認識自己是誰
Would you sometimes miss the time when you
偶爾你是不是會懷念當時那個單純
were rather naive and dared to dream?
勇敢作夢的自己呢
Is that part of you still there?
那個你 現在還在身體裏嗎
Do you still remember those people
而那些生命中很重要的人
who played an important role in your life?
你都還記得嗎
(MY DREAM: GO TO ANDY LAU'S CONCERT...)
(我的夢想: 去看劉德華的演唱會...)
Tonight,
今天晚上
we'll start our program with
我們在節目一開始
this song from me to you all.
就要送給大家這首歌
A song we haven't heard for a long time.
好久沒有聽到的歌
"Forget Love Water" by Andy Lau.
劉德華的忘情水
Good morning. Here is the latest news...
爲您播報晨間新聞
yesterday Alec Su of The Little Tigers
小虎隊成員蘇有朋
said he dropped out of Taiwan University.
昨日宣佈從臺大機械工程系大三休學
The whole entertainment world is in shock.
震驚了所有演圈  · · ·
Are you giving birth? Are you done or not?
你是在生孩子喔 是好了沒啦
I'm done!
好了啦
Back then, I was turning 18
那年即將十八歲的我
and truly understood something important:
深深明白一件很重要的事
History has proven that, there are mainly
從古至今
two types of young girls in the world.
這世上的少女大概分兩種
Hey, here she comes.
出來了  · · ·
Wow! How elegant.
哇塞 她好優雅哦
Oh my God! She's gorgeous!
天啊 她也太漂亮了吧
So cute!
好可愛哦
Pretty girls who are popular...
受男生歡迎的漂亮女生
Don't go!
不要走
- Wait for me! - Tao Minmin!
- 等等我 - 陶敏敏
And
和
those who are not pretty.
不漂亮的
My name is Lin Truly.
我是林真心
Sorry!
對不起
I'm the one who just fell on the street.
是現在仆街的這個
If you're a guy,
如果你男生
let me tell you a story of an ordinary girl
接下來我要告訴你
who you've never bothered to care about
你們從小到大從不想關心的平凡少女
and her ordinary life.
她的平凡人生
= Our Times =
Back then, the most important decision
那時候的我們
we had to make every day
每天最重要的抉擇是
was what to eat for breakfast.
早餐要吃鐵板麪還是蘿蔔糕
Can you please hurry up?
可以快一點嗎
Is it that tough to decide?
有這麼難選嗎
The biggest lie we had ever told
扯過最大的謊是
was on the day of exam,
今天要考試
we'd say...
但  · · ·
I didn't prepare for it.
我昨天沒念耶
Neither did I.
我昨天也沒念耶
I thought we were having math exam.
我以爲要考數學耶
The most luxurious thing to do,
最奢侈的享受
was to go shopping in the bookstore.
是到書局Shopping
Back then,
在那個年代
that was our department store.
那就是我們的新光三越
The biggest dream we had
最大的夢想是
was to meet our idols
有一天
one day.
能和偶像碰面
The shame of being shameless is shameless.
無恥之恥無恥矣 · · ·
Somehow young girls of that time
不知道爲什麼
had some kind of fantasy.
那時候少女有一種錯覺
We believed whoever collected most photos
好像誰買了最多照片
would be the most qualified person
長大以後
to marry him.
誰就最有資格嫁給他
This is Small.
這是小隻
Although large in size,
雖然長得很大隻
she is a super romantic teenage girl.
但是超有少女心
Kaneshiro Takeshi is her ex,
前男友是金城武
and now.
現在
Aaron Kwok is her fiance.
宣稱是郭富城的未婚妻
Even I am not married yet,
我都還沒有嫁人
how come you already have a husband?
你怎麼會有老公
Boss Lau...
劉老大
However hard you try, he'll never reply.
你寫給他三百三十三封他也不會回
What you do is called shameless.
你們倆個的行爲簡直就是無恥的代表
This is Meimei.
這是何美
Very cheerful,
生性活潑
but... almost too cheerful.
但 有點活潑過了頭
Girls, where are you going?
我的好姊妹 你們要去哪裏呀
Back in our teenage life, we were always
少女時代的我們每天除了唸書
doing silly things apart from studying.
做的都是一些窮極無聊的蠢事
And this is the silliest
而以下這件
among all.
更是蠢事中的第一
Ouyang is coming. He's so handsome.
歐陽來了 好帥喔
Hey, be quiet. Come on.
好了 別吵了 趕快看看
He has a style. He's here.
好有型喔 他走過來了
There is always a boy like this,
每個少女的青春裏
in every teenage girl's life.
都有一個這樣的男孩
Thank you.
謝謝
It's on me.
我請客
- 60 please. - 60.
總共六十塊
六十
Somehow they're always basketball players,
不知道爲什麼 他們總是籃球校隊
secret crush for every girl in the school.
不知道爲什麼 全校女生總是一起暗戀他
I feel Ouyang is looking at me.
我覺得歐陽看過來了啦
I think he's looking at me.
我覺得他是在看我耶
We can giggle for the whole day
然後因爲他的一個眼神
just because of a look from him.
傻笑一整天
Dear all, can you please stop helping
麻煩各位同學
those idiots send love letters
不要再幫那些臭男生傳情書
to our Minmin?
給我們的敏敏好嗎
Especially this kind of idiot,
尤其是這種
who misused "disney" for "destiny".
把"緣"寫成"綠"的白癡
This kind of ordinary, simple life
這平凡簡單的人生
was turned upside down by that very letter.
直到收到那封改變一切的信
(TO LIN TRULY)
(林真心 收)
This is a chain letter from South African
這是一封來自南非傳教士
missionary Anthony DE Croud.
Antnony DE Croud的幸運信
Now the good luck is bestowed on you.
現在這個幸運降臨到你的身上
Send 5 copies to your friends,
抄錄五份給你的朋友
and the good luck is yours.
可以得到幸運
Otherwise disasters will be waiting for you.
反之 你將大難臨頭
In 1979, Mr. Chen from Taiwan did not
一九七九年
take the letter seriously and tore it apart.
臺灣的陳先生不信此信將之撕毀
He died in a car accident the next day.
隔天他就車禍身亡
In 1963, Flayre from Holland burnt it...
一九六三年 荷蘭富萊爾將此信燒燬
3 days later, his mother started to...
三天後 他的母親罹患怪病
suffer an incurable disease.
醫生束手無策
(YOU STILL HAVE THREE DAYS. GOOD LUCK.)
(你還有三天時間. 祝你好運.)
The person I want to send chain letter to
我最想把幸運信給他的人
the most, is Lin Sincere.
是林誠意
My brother.
我的哥哥
Your brother advanced
你哥哥這次考試吼
5 places in this exam.
進步了五名吶
Last time he got the lowest score. Besides,
他上次考全班最後一名
he's spent 7 years on a 5-year program...
而且他五專唸了七年還沒畢業
Don't you talk back!
你還頂嘴
Only if you could get half of the grade
你的分數要是有人家那個陶敏敏
of Tao Minmin's.
一半好就好
30 points.
考三十分
You even tried to alter it
還改分數
with a different color.
用不一樣的顏色
How stupid!
怎麼那麼笨吶
My red pen ran out of ink.
啊就紅筆沒有水啊
Couldn't you borrow one from your teacher?
啊不會去跟老師借哦
That's right.
對啊
Take it.
來啦
Thank you mom.
嗯 謝謝媽
Take one more.
多吃一隻
Thank you dad!
謝謝爸
Many of you probably had the same thought,
應該很多人都樣想過
"Am I'm really my parents' child?"
從小我就懷疑自己不是爸媽親生的
But if my brother's family is really ruined,
但考慮到萬一家破人亡
I might suffer as well.
可能會連累到我
So I dismissed that idea.
就打消了念頭
Therefore...
所以
I gave the first letter
第一封信
to him.
我給了他
Lin Truly.
林真心
Question 1:
第一題
If the balls are put in the order of red,
紅藍綠三種顏色的球依序排列
blue, green, what's the color of ball 555?
第五百五十五顆是什麼顏色
It's ok if you don't know the answer,
答不出來就算了
but why drawing it like this?
你畫這麼認真你是在寫生嗎
Don't you dodge!
還躲
There must be a psycho teacher like this
每個人的學生時代
in everyone's school years.
一定都有這樣變態的老師
"Wang Baidan".
"王白丹"
Our home room teacher and math teacher.
我們班導兼數學老師
We all call him.
大家都叫他
"Wang Badan" (ASSHOLE)
"王八蛋"
I haven't even started!
我還沒打咧
Come back.
過來
You're even louder than me.
叫的比我還大聲
I gave the second letter
第二封信
to Tao Minmin.
我寄給了陶敏敏
It's definitely not because I envy her
絕對不是因爲羨慕她漂亮
for her beauty or popularity.
嫉妒她受歡迎
Not even because
更不是因爲
she's that girl who could
她是能被那個 "他"
get his attention.
注意到的女孩
It's simply because she lives next door.
純粹只是因爲她住在我家隔壁
Right on my way home.
順手而已喔
What? A good student?
哎喲好學生喔
Do the recycling.
做資源回收
Hey you.
同學
Kick it back.
踢過來
Ouyang Extraordinary.
歐陽非凡
I might've seen this disgusting name before.
這麼假掰的名字好像在哪裏看過
As there is a "God" in every school,
就像學校裏一定有男神
there is also a "boss".
每間學校也一定有個老大
Stand up.
起立
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Last number of the last class in 3rd grade.
三年級最後一班最後一號
He's the boss who leads our school in
就是那個代表一高和別的學校爭地盤
turf wars and charge others protection fee.
收保護費的老大
Rumor has it that
傳聞
he fights, runs away from home, he's on drug
他打架  械鬥 逃家 吸毒
has killed people, set fire...
殺過人 縱過火
So notorious that no school wants him,
惡名遠播到整區高中聯合拒收
except for First High School...
只有一高願意收留他
How daring are you to be here.
敢來這裏囂張
You despise us the 12 Masters of First High?
瞧不起我們一高十二少
What about Ten Brothers from Chuoshui River?
林北還濁水溪十兄弟
Kill them.
乎死
He's even appointed as school patrol.
學校還以毒攻毒讓他擔任糾察隊
Indecent clothing.
服儀不整
Eating while walking.
邊走邊吃
Studying too hard.
書讀太多
Too matured body.
發育太好
First High...
一高
has since been trapped in the devil's clutches.
就此被困在他的魔掌之中
Recycle it!
資源回收
Hey, what are you doing?
喂  幹什麼
Why bully others like this?
你爲什麼要這樣欺負別人
What the hell are you guys doing?
在幹什麼
Here comes the director,
主任來了
let's go.
老大 快閃
Come on! Go, go.
趕快走 快一點 · · ·
Chicken.
臭俗仔
Therefore...
所以我決定
I decided to send him the third letter.
寄出第三封信
Guile.
阿力固
G your mother.
阿你的頭啦
Sorry
(TO HSU TAIYU)
It's pink
粉紅色
with fragrance.
有香味
Love letter?
情書耶
Aren't you over the moon, boss?
老大爽不爽啊
Over what! Get lost.
爽你個頭 閃啦
Who has the guts to write him a love letter?
哪個不怕死的居然敢寫情書給他
Oh, he was even blushing.
哦 他剛還臉紅
Blushing! Hahahaha.
臉紅耶 哈 · · ·
He must be over the moon now.
他在心裏一定超爽的
Not just over the moon...
什麼爽而已
Over the whole world!
簡直是爽翻天啦
老大 · · ·
Boss.
Did you hear about it already?
你們倆個有沒有聽說
Hsu Taiyu had a car accident yesterday.
那個徐太宇昨天出車禍了耶
Lin Truly...
林真心 · · ·
If I find out who cursed boss,
如果被我抓到是誰詛咒老大的
I'll make sure to break his arms and legs.
林北絕對乎他斷手斷腳
Sorry, she needs to take her medicine.
對不起 她該吃藥了
Lin Truly, let's go.
林真心 走啦 · · ·
Why are you so heavy!
你怎麼那麼重啊
Go.
走了啦
Boss, watch your step.
老大小心
Someone is spreading the rumor,
有同學在謠傳
saying this year's school anniversary
說今年的校慶
will be suspended due to track renovation.
會因爲整修跑道而停辦
Let me clarify it here.
我在這裏鄭重說明
This year, school anniversary festival
今年的校慶
will be held as scheduled.
會如期舉行
Since I'm retiring from First High soon.
個人即將在一高退休了
The new director will take over
接任的訓導主任
the responsibility as the organizer.
屆時將會承辦相關的事宜
Last but not least, do not leave yet.
最後呢 請各位同學先不要離開
School patrol is now conducting
糾察隊
a surprise safety inspection.
現在正在各班實施突擊安全檢查
Dahe.
大賀
Breast baring.
露點
That's too nasty.
太嚴重啦
Make a note.
記起來
Confiscate it.
沒收
Hey you.
同學
We need to talk.
有事找你
Where are we going?
我們現在要去哪裏啊
Just follow us.
走就對了
No!
我不要
Enjoy, boss.
老大請享用
In 1979,
一九七九年
Mr. Chen from Taiwan...
臺灣的陳先生
did not take the letter seriously
不信此信
and tore it apart.
將之撕毀
The next day he died in a car accident.
隔天就車禍身亡
So it's you.
原來是這樣
Whose films do you like?
你喜歡誰的電影
蛤
What?
Who?
誰的啦
S...Stephen Chow.
周 · · · 周星馳
Which film do you like best?
你最喜歡他哪一部片
All... "All's Well, Ends Well".
家 · · ·家家家有囍事
How many "all" s?
幾個家
One.
一個家
Your birthday?
生日
April 19.
四月十九
Good, you're honest.
很好 沒有說謊
What don't you like about me?
你對我有什麼意見
Nothing.
沒有意見
I...think... you're
我 · · ·覺得 · · ·你
tall...
又高
and cute...
又帥
and if I look closely...
近看
You even look a bit like Andy Lau?
還很像劉德華耶
I know you sent the chain letter to me
我知道你爲了他
because of him.
才寄幸運信給我的
No!
不可以
What no?
啥米不可以
I can't change the film?
換片不可以喔
Would you like to change the film?
客人要換片嗎
Yes, to...
換
All... "All's Well, Ends Well".
家 · · ·家家有囍事吧
Sure, just a moment.
好 稍等
Let's...
我們
be friends.
交個朋友吧
What?
蛤
You just introduced yourself.
剛剛你已經自我介紹完啦
In Taiyu's dictionary, friend means
徐太宇對"朋友"的定義
unconditional devotion.
就是無條件對他付出
In order to protect Ouyang,
爲了保護歐陽的安危
I'm willing to listen to Hsu Taiyu.
我只能聽命于徐太宇
Be his slave.
做他的奴隸
Auntie.
老闆娘
One sesame noodle.
我要一碗麻醬麪
Don't put sesame dressing and noodles
麻醬跟面
together. They need to be separated.
它們不可以放在一起要分開
No fatty no lean for braised pork rice
然後滷肉飯不要肥肉也不要瘦肉
but half half.
要半肥半瘦
And veggie tofu soup without spring onion.
然後青菜豆腐湯
Two eggs in it but don't beat it.
兩顆蛋 不要蔥花也不要打成蛋花
Thank you.
謝謝
If no spring onion in veggie tofu soup,
青菜豆腐湯都不要加蔥花
why have it on sesame noodles?
爲什麼麻醬麪上面有蔥花
Get a new one!
重買
Wait.
等一下
This is your reward.
獎勵你的
Autographed photo of Andy Lau.
劉德華簽名照
It's Andy Low from the TV show.
是百戰百勝 "劉的華"
Here.
這邊
I thought you forgot your book for math
你不是數學課要校外教學沒帶課本嗎
excursion, where are the other people?
其他人咧
Idiot.
白癡
What kind of excursion for math class?
誰數學課校外教學啊
Hurry up.
快點
The movie starts at 2.
電影兩點開始
Ah...
欵
The bell rang already, I'm going back.
已經打鐘了 我要回去上課了
Then who'll get food for me?
那誰幫我買吃的
Who'll collect my trash?
誰幫我收垃圾
Who'll fan for me?
誰幫我扇風
I can't climb the wall.
我不會翻牆
So...
所以
I really can't do this.
真的不行啦
You wanna die?
你想死嗎
What if the teacher finds out?
被老師發現怎麼辦啊
I've never skipped class in my life...
我從來沒有翹過課
If you've never done that in your uniform,
沒穿過高中制服翹過一次課
you'll regret in the future.
長大以後纔會後悔好嗎
You're so heavy.
好重
Hurry up.
快點溜
Don't goof off.
不要混
Can I go back for tutorial class?
我可不可以回去上輔導課啊
Attach yourself to the end of the line.
你等一下接在最後面
Hsu Taiyu, I had enough!
徐太宇 我不想玩了
Are you ok?
沒事吧
Are you alright?
還好嗎
I'm ok...
沒事
Then go get squid balls for me!
那去幫我買花枝丸
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Thank you.
謝謝
Go away! What are you looking at? Sit down.
閃啦 看啥 坐好啦
Quickly!
快走
Sit!
坐下
Sit tight!
坐好啦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Don't you dare touch my gal...
林北ㄟ七辣你也敢動
幹嘛
What's wrong!
Holding hands when roller skating?
溜冰還手牽手
How can you do it without holding hands?
啊溜冰是不用手牽手膩
Shut up!
還頂嘴
What?
欵
Kill him.
乎死啊
Sakuraki.
櫻木
Boss.
老大
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Boss, are you ok?
老大你沒事吧
It's ok.
沒事啦
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
If I didn't have final exam this afternoon,
要不是林北下午要期末考
I'll never let you get away with it!
我絕對不會放過你
Let's go back to study!
走  回去K 書
I'll get you, you motherfucker!
相遇的到
(NO DISTINCTION OF CLASSES IN TEACHING.)
Miss Lin.
林同學
I know you're innocent.
我知道你是無辜的
If you to tell me
你只要告訴主任
what happened at the skating rink,
溜冰場當天的情況
you won't be punished.
沒你的事兒
I...
那天
Cold.
感冒
I don't... remember
那天  發生什麼事情
what happened when where who at all.
我不知道 不清楚 不記得了啦
Right. You went to indecent place
好 你翹課到不良場所
during school hours. Your punishment is
罰你愛校服務
10 hours of pool cleaning.
清理泳池十個小時
回去
Go back to your class.
Thank you, sir.
謝謝主任
What were you doing?
你們幾個搞什麼東西
School patrol skipped the class?
自己是糾察隊還翹課
Hey, school patrol!
喂 你們這個臭糾察隊的
Lin Truly!
林真心
How come you were in the office with Taiyu?
你怎麼會和徐太宇被叫到訓導處啊
Shhhh... for what?
噓 · · · 什麼
We can't what?
不能什麼
I see! How many words?
哦  幾個字 · · ·
Ouyang!
歐陽
Ouyang what?
歐陽什麼啊
See...
看
your face.
臉 · · ·你
We can't let Ouyang see you.
歐陽不能看到你
Yes!
Yes
Lin Truly?
林真心
想不到你還滿厲害的嘛
I didn't know you're actually pretty good.
I also like roller skating too.
我也很喜歡溜冰
Next time we can go together.
有機會一起去啊
Lin Truly.
林真心
Ouyang knows your name!
歐陽他知道你的名字耶
And even asked you out...
他還約你出去耶
Praised by Ouyang for skipping class...
翹課還被歐陽稱讚
Strangely amazing.
這也太離奇了吧
Look, love fire is burning.
看愛火在燃燒
Love fire is bouncing.
愛火在跳躍
Warmly, our hearts
我們的心
embrace each other.
暖暖擁抱
I told my mom...
我媽知道了 · · ·
Did she give her approval?
她同意嗎
Yes.
嗯
But...
可是
What if the teacher finds out
我們這樣被老師發現
about us...?
怎麼辦
This is not allowed by the school.
學校是不準的
Don't worry.
不用擔心
I am the father.
我是爸爸
I'll take the responsibility.
我會負責的
So glad you're here.
幸好有你在
You should go now!
回去吧
Others can come here anytime.
學生會中途跑出來
大家會起疑的
They'll find us suspicious.
Was someone here?
剛有人來過嗎
What should we do?
怎麼辦
Will people find out about us?
我們的事不會被發現吧
We'll be fine.
沒事的
Let's get out of here now.
我們趕快離開這裏
What the fuck are you looking at!
看屁啊
Did you just try to drown yourself?
你剛是不是想淹死自己
Just for that prick?
就爲了那個白癡
Then what on earth are you crying for?
那你在哭什麼啊
You're the silly one...
你才白癡咧
Do you have it with you all the time?
你上課都隨身攜帶這些哦
If you never had beer in your uniform...
沒穿過高中制服 喝過幾罐啤酒 長大以後
I'll regret in the future.
我會後悔
I got it.
知道啦
You wrote this?
這是你寫的哦
You like Tao Minmin?
你喜歡陶敏敏
Dear Tao Minmin:
陶敏敏同學
When you were trying the hairpin yesterday,
昨天你在新學友書局試戴髮夾
I really longed to touch...
一頭烏黑的長髮
the beautiful black hair of yours!
讓人好想摸一下
You're so sick.
變態啊你
Because...
因爲
It's so nice to meet you
認識你真好
do you know that?
知不知道
Quoting lyrics... you really suck.
爛透了還抄歌詞
Now we're both kind of...
我們現在也算是
Association of the Dumped members.
失戀陣線聯盟
For the first time I think you're clever.
第一次覺得你聰明
What?
幹嘛
Let's help them break up.
一起讓他們分手吧
If you help me chase Tao Minmin...
幫我追陶敏敏
wouldn't that make your Ouyang
你的歐陽
single again?
不就單身了嗎
Sorry! Sorry!
對不起
Excuse me!
借過
Did you bring powdered milk and bottle?
你有帶奶粉和奶瓶嗎
Yeah.
有啊
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Sorry...
對不起哦
Mommy's late.
媽媽太晚來了
You must be starving.
你肚子一定餓壞了哦
Slowly... slowly.
乖 慢慢吃哦
Look at the eyes...
你看他的眼睛
So adorable.
好可愛哦
Just like you.
跟你好像哦
Should we take it to the vet for shots?
我們是不是要帶它去打預防針
Yeah. Let's do it after school soon.
嗯 找天放學我們一起帶它去
OK.
好
We misunderstood them.
哎喲 我們誤會了啦
There is nothing between them.
他們根本就沒什麼
Just a puppy.
只是一起養狗啊
Having a dog now together means
雖然現在只是一起養狗
they'll walk the dog together. Get closer.
以後就會一起溜狗
Then the dog will have more puppies.
日久生情 狗又生狗
We can't let this happen.
不能讓這種事發生
Say that again. What do you think of me?
再說一次你覺得我怎麼樣
You're tall...
又高
and cute...
又帥
If I look closely...
近看
You even look a bit like Andy Lau.
還有點像劉德華
《追夢人》鳳飛飛
讓青春吹動了你的長髮讓它牽引你的夢
不知不覺這城市的歷史已記取了你的笑容
紅紅心中藍藍的天是個生命的開始
春雨不眠隔夜的你曾空獨眠的日子
Tao Minmin!
陶敏敏
The campus belle!
校花喔
So pretty!
好漂亮喔
Our boss is hot!
老大好帥
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏同學
Wanna be my gal?
要不要做我女朋友
大嫂 · · ·
Say yes, Say yes.
今天的事誰敢說出去
If you dare to tell others what happened,
you are dead.
誰就死定了
Don't you tell others boss is dumped.
老大被甩誰敢說出去誰就死定了
Let me repeat.
我再說一次
Don't you tell others boss is dumped.
老大被甩誰敢說出去誰就死定了
What the fuck!
講三小啊
Get lost!
滾
Quick!
快滾啦
Get out of there!
快滾
Hsu Taiyu...
徐太宇
I think... we should give up.
我看 我們還是放棄好了
Tao Minmin... will not be attracted by you.
陶敏敏 不會喜歡你這一型的啦
There is no such word like "give up".
我的字典裏沒有放棄
(REPORT STRAY DOGS TO HAVE THEM CAUGHT.)
As long as the dog is gone,
只要那隻狗消失
they won't have excuse to meet each other.
他們就沒有理由見面
Don't do silly things.
你不要衝動
I got it!
我有辦法
Hurry up.
動作快
Puppy... they'll think you ran away...
狗狗 就讓人家以爲是你自己跑掉的
you're not stolen.
不是被偷走的哦
Hurry up!
快一點
Someone's coming.
有人來了啦
Such a stupid idea.
想什麼爛招啊
Where can he go?
現在要帶它去哪
Who's gonna take care of him?
誰有空照顧它啊
I thought you were really that cruel,
我還以爲你真的那麼狠
that you wouldn't care if he dies.
會不管它死活
Before you can find him a new owner,
找到人收養它以前
he's staying with you.
你給我帶回家
Why the fuck do you pee...
怎麼尿尿
Quick!
快點啦
Alright, alright.
哎喲 好啦 · · ·
What should we call him?
我們要叫它什麼
What about...
叫
Andy?
"華仔"
You like it?
怎麼樣
No way.
我纔不要咧
How can you humiliate my idol like this!
你怎麼可以這樣污衊我的偶像啊
Besides...
而且
It's a she.
它是母的耶
ND the alphabets.
瓦斯的瓦
Anything wrong?
不行膩
ND... ND...
瓦仔 · · ·
See! She doesn't like it!
你看它不要啦
Why not?
爲什麼不要
Because you can't humiliate my idol!
因爲你不可以這樣污衊我的偶像
Besides, she's a girl! -ND!
- 而且人家是少女 - 瓦仔
I'm gonna rub some dog pee on your head.
我拿尿摸你的頭哦
- ND... - Hsu Taiyu!
- 瓦仔 - 徐太宇
(REPORT STRAY DOGS TO HAVE THEM CAUGHT.)
好像真的被捕狗大隊抓走了
It seems like he's really caught...
昨天找了好久
I looked for her everywhere...
搞不好它被它主人找回去啦
Maybe she's just taken back by her owner.
值日生咧
Who's on duty today?
擦黑板啊
Clean it up!
我給你們方便你們當隨便啊
You have no respect for your teacher...
起立
Stand up.
不用了
No need.
是誰
Who did this?
拿這種無聊的東西來詛咒別人
Cursing others with this silly stuff!
等一下到我辦公室 自首
Come to my office and turn yourself in.
我不要求考託福
Excuse me.
報告
You should at least take exams.
至少你考試要出席嘛
You don't remember what I said?
老師的話都是從左耳進右耳出的嗎
I got an anonymous letter saying you did it.
有同學匿名舉發說幸運信是你寄來的
You know.
你知道
I remain unmarried for so many years,
我這麼多年沒有結婚
devoting myself to you...
犧牲奉獻給你
I mean...
不是
to the school.
給學校
Can't you just do me a favor?
你就不能給我個面子嗎
It's ok.
沒關係
Tell me the truth...
你說實話
I'm very understanding.
老師很開明的
Listen...
我告訴你哦
If I find out that you're lying to me later,
你如果現在說謊後來被發現
I'll have no choice but to punish you.
那老師就只好處罰你了
I know who wrote it.
我知道信是誰寫的
Wrote what?
什麼信
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
You...
你
I wrote it.
是我寫的
Very good.
非常好
Miss Lin.
林同學
You can go now.
你回去
Thank you.
是
I knew it!
我就知道是你
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I really wish it's not you again.
枉費我一直對你存着一絲希望
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
我跟你講了一半你怎麼可以走開
How can you leave in the middle of my talk?
Ms. Chen.
陳老師
Let me punish him first.
你先讓我罰他
Mr. Wang, I haven't finished yet.
王老師我這邊比較嚴重
Let me scold him first.
你讓我先罵他
It's not a matter of...
不是什麼比較嚴重還是
No, I was in the middle of scolding him.
沒有我剛剛講到一半我正在教訓他
One thing at one time.
一個一個來
Don't rush.
不要急
You first.
你先
OK.
好
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why do you think the school still took you in
你覺得三年級才轉學
even though it's your last year in high school?
爲什麼一高還願意收你進來
Because you were in science honors class.
那是因爲你國中唸的是數理資優班
Even attended Science Olympiad competition.
還代表學校參加奧林匹亞的競賽
What happened to you?
爲什麼你現在會變成這樣
Have you heard of "The Tortoise and the Hare"?
聽過龜兔賽跑的故事嗎
And "Eradicating the Three Scourges".
還有改過自新的周處除三害
Do you know who's "Zhou Chu"?
周處知道是誰嗎
Yeah.
知道
It's pronounced "Chu" not "Choo"...
那個字念處哦 · · ·不是處哦
Thank you.
謝謝
You...
其實
really didn't have to do that.
你可以不用幫我頂罪的
That's what a friend is for.
朋友就是要講義氣啊
It does me no harm anyway.
我又沒差
One chain letter to me...
你一封信給我
One to "Asshole"...
一封信給王八蛋
Two others taken away by me...
兩封都被我沒收啦
Who got the last one?
你還有一封給誰
Tao Minmin...
陶敏敏
I really regret for it.
我也很後悔啊
That's why...
所以
You should work hard to get her!
你纔要好好追人家嘛
Girls like her must have had
像她這樣的女生啊
enough of compliments.
稱讚一定聽膩了
Why not write bad things about her
不如寫一下她的缺點
to get her attention?
吸引她的注意力
For example...
譬如說
Thick waist...
腰粗
Huge butt...
屁股大
So fake when she talks...
講話很假掰之類的
You sure?
你確定
Yeah.
嗯
And conclude it with...
然後最後再補一句
But still...
即使這樣
I like you a lot.
我還是很喜歡你
Hey.
欵
Don't quote lyrics if you have no good idea.
沒有靈感不要抄歌詞啦
You can quote foreign poets' work.
可以抄外國詩人的作品
Who's gonna understand it?
誰看得懂
That's why it'll make you look mysterious.
就是看不懂才覺得你高深莫測啊
You sure?
你確定
Sure.
真的
Let me tell you.
我跟你說哦
Girls are so difficult to understand.
女生啊是很難捉摸地
When we say nothing's wrong...
我們說沒事
it means something's wrong.
就是有事
When we say it's ok,
我們說沒關係
it means it's not ok.
就是有關係
If we say...
如果我們今天說
I am fat...
我很胖
That means we hope you can tell us...
那就代表她希望你對她說
You're not fat at all.
她一點都不胖
That's the way...
陶敏敏
Tao Minmin thinks.
就是這樣想的
(CHONGDE JUNIOR HIGH YEARBOOK)
(HSU TAIYU)
I'll do this.
我來做這個
You pick that one.
你選那一個
(OUYANG EXTRAORDINARY)
Don't stop.
你們繼續練啊
Watch out.
看路喔
Ouyang Extraordinary...
歐陽非凡
You actually...
你其實
know Hsu Taiyu quite well.
跟徐太宇很熟
Right?
對不對
What?
怎樣
Did you watch the Bulls vs. Lakers game?
昨天公牛跟湖人隊的比賽有沒有看
Of course.
當然有啊
Shit, what a dramatic victory.
大逆轉
Jordan is God!
喬丹超神的啦
So dramatic!
大逆轉啦
One-on-one if you dare.
有種來打賭啦
3 minutes.
三分鐘
Whoever swims farther wins.
誰遊得遠誰就贏
Bring it on.
Who怕Who啊
C'mon.
來啊
A-yuan.
阿遠
A-yuan...
阿遠 · · ·
A-yuan.
阿遠
Hsu Taiyu, don't go further.
徐太宇不要再過去了 徐太宇
Ma Suyuan.
馬思遠
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Taiyu thought the accident wouldn't have.
太宇覺得如果不是他答應跟阿遠比賽
A-yuan.
阿遠
Happened, if he didn't take the challenge.
或許意外就不會發生
That was the last time
從那天起
I saw Hsu Taiyu,
我就再也沒看過徐太宇
before he transferred to First High.
直到他轉學來到一高
He became someone I don't know.
變成了一個我不認識的人
Why don't we meet at Ice Palace,
幹嘛不去冰宮
but here?
約在這裏
You feel embarrassed?
怕丟臉
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Let's have a race.
我們來比賽
The winner can make a request.
贏的可以要求對方做一件事
Whoever crosses that line first wins.
誰先到那條線誰就贏
You can never beat me.
你贏不了我的啦
Stop or you'll kill yourself.
再這樣下去會摔死
What's wrong with you?
你吃錯藥啊
When you saw me in the pool the other day,
那天你看到我在游泳池裏
were you afraid that I'd die like Su-yuan,
你是不是怕我跟馬思遠一樣
in front of your eyes.
在你面前溺死
Ouyang told me everything.
歐陽告訴我了
None of your business.
幹你屁事啊
Who are you to shout at me?
你憑什麼兇我啊
Who are you to hurt yourself like this?
你憑什麼把自己搞成這個樣子
It's also not easy for Ouyang, ok?
歐陽也很難過好不好
Ma Suyuan must be pissed off
馬思遠也一定很不爽
to see the way you are now.
你變成現在這個樣子
Don't make me beat you!
不要以爲我不敢揍你哦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
If I could do it over again,
如果剛剛重來一次
I'd still have a race with you.
我還是會和你比賽
If A-yuan could do it over again,
如果再重來一次
he'd still go into the sea.
阿遠還是下海
But it's our own decision.
可是這是我們的決定
Not your responsibility.
不用你來負責啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
You agreed that
你剛答應過
the winner can make a request.
贏的人可以要求對方做一件事
What do you want?
什麼
Can you...
你可不可以
be that Hsu Taiyu again?
做回徐太宇
Stand up!
起立
A...attention.
敬 · · ·敬禮
Good morning, sir.
老師好
Shut up!
上課
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇同學
Do you...
你
have any question?
有什麼問題嗎
Yes.
有
Which page are we at today?
今天上第幾頁
Chapter 7 on page 125.
第一百二十五頁第七章
World War 2.
第二次世界大戰
Hsu...
徐同學
You have
你翻的是
geography textbook in your hand.
地理課本耶
Chapter 7.
第七章
Page 125.
第一百二十五頁
Take your textbook out!
課本拿出來啦
Those who don't have it...
沒帶課本的
go and sit next to those who do.
找有課本的一起看
Am I cute?
我可愛嗎
Wow!
哇塞
Miss.
小姐
You look familiar...
你有點面熟
You are my high school...
你是我的高中
teacher.
老師
What's wrong with you today?
你今天干嘛
Going to temple festival?
要去廟會哦
Not really.
沒有啦
I...
我
Hurry up!
快點啦
We need to secure our seats at McDonald's!
太晚去麥當勞會沒位子
Temple festival is this way...
廟會在那邊啦
Look at that guy...
你看那個男生
- So cute... - Look, it's him...
- 好帥哦 - 你看 就是他
so tall.
好高哦
So cute...
好帥哦
You idiot.
白癡哦
Look where you're going.
走路不看路
You got a hole in your brain?
腦袋有洞
It's fine.
沒關係啦
Let's look for a seat first
我們先上去找位子
and order later.
等一下 下來點餐
You're gonna help me.
你要幫我喔
OK.
好啦
Here's what you ordered.
你的餐點都已經到齊了
Thanks.
謝謝
Have a nice meal.
祝你用餐愉快
Hello! Welcome!
你好歡迎光臨
What would you like to order?
請問要點什麼
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
He's studying there.
他在那邊溫書耶
It seems like he really changed.
看來他真的轉性羅
Maybe he's here...
搞不好啊
because you come here often.
他是因爲你常來這裏他纔來的呀
- Let's go... - What?
- 走啦 -  幹嘛啦
Hey, she wants to talk to you.
欵 她有話跟你說
I'll find us a table.
我先去佔位子
That seat is...
那個位子
Hsu...
徐同學
I heard you were in science honors class...
聽說你以前是資優班的
If that's the case,
如果是這樣的話
you should never give up.
你千萬不要放棄
If there's something you don't understand,
課業上如果有什麼問題
I can help you with it.
我可以幫你
Thanks.
謝啦
You asked me to give you my personal info.
你之前要我回的個人檔案
You'll have it.
我會回
But...
但是
Don't mistake "Disney" for "Destiny" again.
下次不要再把"緣"寫成"綠" 了
Why "Destiny"?
什麼緣啊
Disney is my pseudonym.
綠是我的筆名啊
What... were you... talking about?
剛 敏敏 找你幹嘛
Nothing. They wanted to share the table.
沒幹嘛 想並桌
Study.
讀書啊
Hsu Taiyu started to study hard.
徐太宇開始認真唸書
Very hard.
很認真
Although I think it's because I woke him up,
雖然很想把這歸功於我打醒他
the truth is...
但事實是
he did it for Minmin.
他爲了敏敏
He wants to get into top 10
這次模擬考
in the coming mock exam.
他想考進英雄榜
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Did he come to see you?
他該不會是來看你的吧
Back then...
在那個年代
if a girl
一個女生
was willing to give you her personal info,
願意回你她的個人資料
that means...
就代表
she didn't dislike you at all.
她對你還算有一點點好感
(THE PERSON I LIKE:)
Latest version of sample exams, good luck.
這最新的考古題 考試加油
Thank you.
謝謝
會的 謝謝老闆
Ah.
啊
It's my hubby.
我的老公耶
When I grow up.
我長大以後啊
I will go to Taipei for your concert...
一定要去臺北看你的演唱會
A piece of cake.
那有什麼難的
One day I'll ask Andy Lau
以後我叫劉德華
to sing for you.
唱給你聽
Really?
真的
Yeah right.
最好是啦
Hey! Don't touch it!
喂 不要碰
Let's go.
快走
If we add the two together...
這兩個加在一起
Idiot.
笨蛋
Sin^2(X) + cos^2(X) = 1.
Sin X絕對值平方加Cos X絕對值平方
No exception.
永遠等於一
What?
嗯
Look behind you.
看後面
Wow... when did Truly become so serious?
哇 林真心什麼時候變那麼認真
Something's wrong with Boss... hehe.
老大怪怪的哦
I live just down there.
我家就在前面
It's quite late.
已經很晚了
You should go home now.
你先走啦
Oh...
哦
It's ok.
沒關係啊
If I linger a bit,
再一下
I might run into Tao Minmin.
搞不好會遇到陶敏敏
Oh...
哦
By the way.
對了
ND already learned to pee at the same spot.
瓦仔 現在已經會在固定的地方尿尿了
Thank God...
謝天謝地
she didn't grow into an idiot like you.
幸好沒被你養笨
For me?
送我啊
I planned to give it to Tao Minmin.
本來是要送陶敏敏的
But it's so ugly and it's Andy Lau...
但是這麼醜又是劉德華
better give it to you.
跟你比較配
Hey...
那個
tell me, for guys...
我問你哦
what's the definition of pretty girls?
男生 到底覺得什麼樣的女生漂亮
You mean what kind of girls Ouyang likes?
你想問歐陽喜歡怎麼樣的女生吧
Whatever.
隨便啦
Anything.
都可以
He was crazy about Vivian Chow before.
他以前很迷周慧敏
What about you?
那你呢
Uchida Yuki is not bad.
內田有紀還不錯
Sakai Noriko also.
還有酒井法子
Both Japanese?
都日本女生哦
Yes.
是
I want to learn roller skating.
我最近想學溜冰
Why so sudden?
幹嘛突然想學
Because...
就 · · ·
Ouyang says he likes roller skating.
歐陽說他喜歡溜冰啊
You're pretty good... can you teach me?
你那麼厲害 可以教我嗎
Sure.
好啊
I want this.
這個
Hello, Mr. Tang.
湯叔叔好
Should I ask my bro to come down?
要不要幫你叫我哥下來
Where can I get the same look as yours?
去哪裏才能弄得跟你一樣啊
Go to hell and get reborn will be easier.
去地獄重新投胎比較快啦
Lin Truly, are you hitting puberty?
林真心 你思春哦
Don't be so mean.
你很壞
It's normal for girls to care their looks.
小女生都想要變漂亮啊
Let me help you.
姐姐幫你
Thank you sis.
謝謝大嫂
Are you alright?
你還好嗎
Yeah, sprained my ankle, that's all.
沒事只是練球扭到而已
Just need to ice it a bit.
冰敷一下就好了
Ouyang got injured. Does Truly know?
歐陽受傷了 真心知道嗎
I don't know...
不知道
Let's tell her when she's here.
等她來我們趕快去跟她講好了
Hey hey.
奇怪
Are you close friends of Ouyang's?
歐陽跟你們很熟嗎
Ouyang!
歐陽
- Chiayi, you... - Calm down.
- 沈家儀你真的 - 息怒 · · ·
Are you alright?
你還好吧
Yeah.
還好
Wow it swells so much.
哇這腫得很厲害
No way, we must heat it.
不行 這一定要熱敷一下
Ice it.
是冰敷啦
Heat it! Were you there in health class?
是熱敷啦 你有沒有在上健康教育
Hey...
這個
I always ice with this when I'm injured.
我受傷的時候都用這個冰敷
Convenient and tasty.
方便又好吃
Thanks.
謝啦
看樣子我不用去保健室了
Guess I don't have to visit health center.
I'll go back to class now.
我先去上課
You look cute today.
今天滿可愛的
The hairstyle suits you.
這髮型很適合你
Good luck with your exam.
段考加油
Wow!
哇
So cute.
可愛哦
Lin Truly, you are so pretty.
林真心你好漂亮哦
I want to look like you!
我也想跟你一樣
He said you're cute!
被稱讚羅
Did you put on makeup?
你是不是有化妝啊
Hsu Taiyu got 10th place in the mock exam
那次三年級模擬考
among all 3rd year students.
徐太宇進了英雄榜第十名
While the whole school was still in shock,
在全校爲他震驚時
the new director arrived.
新的訓導主任來了
Littering.
亂丟垃圾
Which eye of yours saw that I littered?
你哪隻眼睛看到我亂丟垃圾
You are the litter.
你就是垃圾
Director Chuan said...
全主任說
Everyone in class 317...
你們317的人
is a piece of shit.
都是垃圾
Fuck! What the hell!
靠北哦
School regulation says "no hair coloring".
校規明訂 禁止學生染髮
The new director hates people who break the rules.
我們全主任最討厭破壞校規的人
Excuse me.
報告
Hsu Taiyu from class 317.
317的徐太宇
Finally.
終於見面了
You'd better be good until you graduate.
你最好在畢業之前安分一點
Otherwise I'll kick you out of the school
否則三大過一滿
once you're cited with 3 serious demerits.
我一定退你學
As you wish.
退就退啊
I'll do my best.
我會盡力而爲
Because people like you
因爲像你們這種人
do not deserve education at all.
根本就不配受教育
Stand up.
起立
Who got first place in the exam this time?
你們班這次段考第一名的同學是誰
Please stand up.
請起立
Let's give him a big hand.
大家掌聲鼓勵
Good job.
真的很厲害
So good that I have to ask Hsu...
厲害到我想請問一下徐同學
how did you cheat in the exam?
這次考試你是怎麼作弊來的
I asked people to give you a big hand
我剛纔叫大家鼓掌
to see if you know what is shame!
是想看看你有沒有羞恥心
You just talked, stand up!
那位講話的同學站起來
Sir.
報告主任
I didn't talk.
我沒有講話
I have eyes to judge that.
有沒有講話我自己有眼睛看
Did you help him...
這次考試
in the exam?
你有沒有幫忙他
Can someone come forward and testify that.
有哪位同學可以出來作證
Hsu Taiyu cheated.
徐太宇作弊
No one wants to tell the truth, huh?
沒有人肯說實話是不是
Now...
現在
All of you, go to the running track.
全班到操場跑步
Stand up!
起立
I know you dislike me...
你看我不順眼
but it has nothing to do with them!
幹他們屁事啊
Leave them alone.
要罰就罰我一個
Fine.
好
Want to play the hero?
愛逞英雄嘛
I'll leave all 50 rounds to you.
那就五十圈都讓你跑
Run to your heart's content.
跑個夠
Director Chuan must be sick. So strict.
全主任有病吧 服儀抓這麼嚴
Demerit for skirts above the knees.
對啊 裙子沒到膝下就被記過
A lap is 400 meters!
這一圈有四百公尺
I heard that Hsu already finished 35 rounds.
對啊 他已經跑第三十五圈了
I heard that he cheated in the exam
聽說徐太宇考試作弊
and started a battle with the director.
跟主任槓上了
He's punished to run 50 rounds.
所以被罰跑操場五十圈
He's not that kind of person.
他纔不是那種人
Minmin, Chiayi is bullshiting.
陶敏敏你不要聽沈家儀亂講
Lin Truly...
林真心
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why don't you tell the truth?
你爲什麼不說實話
Hsu Taiyu!
徐太宇
Excuse me.
借過一下
Director.
主任
Hsu Taiyu really didn't cheat.
徐太宇同學真的沒有作弊
I can testify for him.
我可以作證
He really studied very hard.
他真的很努力的唸書
You should stay away from people like him.
你們升學班的最好少跟那種人混在一起
Tell him,
告訴他
if he can't finish, 1 more demerit for him.
今天要是沒跑完我一定記他一支大過
Plus one-week suspension from school.
外加禁學一個禮拜
Let him reflect on himself at home.
讓他在家好好反省
How's your boss doing?
你們老大現在還好嗎
Dunno...
不知道
He doesn't answer on his pager.
call機他都沒回
I heard that the school festival next week
聽說下禮拜校慶
might be cancelled by the director.
主任想要取消耶
He said we students don't study enough.
是說什麼學生太沉迷外務
What the fuck is he thinking!
聽他放屁啊
Students also deserve human rights!
學生就不能夠有人權嗎
The authority shouldn't let him bully us!
學校怎麼可以讓他這樣欺負我們
Of course not!
當然不可以
We'll let the authority hear our voice
下個禮拜校慶
at the school festival next week.
要讓學校聽到我們的聲音
Let him know he can't do whatever he likes.
讓主任知道他不能爲所欲爲
Let's do it!
好
Sorry.
不好意思
- Please stand up for our rights - Please.
-  同學  站出來 - 麻煩你  拜託
Please, the revolt needs your support.
同學 一高起義需要你的支持
The revolt needs your support.
一高起義需要你的支持
Please have a look...
同學 · · ·請看一下 · · ·
Please, please have a look.
同學 · · ·看一下
Please support First High's revolt.
一高起義請支持
一高起義請多支持
Please, please have a look.
同學 · · ·你看一下
We really really
你們的支持
need your support.
對我們真的很重要
Don't take it.
不要啦
You're done if the director knows.
被主任知道就完了耶
Leave it to me.
交給我
Hand it out over there. You, there.
你去發那邊 你去那邊
You're openly instigating others to revolt,
你這是公然煽動同學
violating the regulations,
違綱亂紀
humiliating your teachers.
侮辱師長
Everyone who helped you now has a demerit.
你害那些幫你的同學現在全部都被記過了
Do your parents know what you're doing?
你爸媽知道你幹這事兒嗎
You brought disgrace on your parents.
你讓父母蒙羞
You brought shame on them.
你丟你爸媽的臉
The teacher said Hsu is a gangster.
老師說那個徐太宇是流氓學生耶
He's not even allowed to go to school!
學校不讓他上學你看他有多壞
You completely destroyed my reputation.
我的臉都被你丟光了啦
You... go upstairs and write your confession.
你 · · ·現在給我上去寫悔過書
You're grounded for two days.
兩天不準出門
Now!
現在
How embarrassing.
真是丟人現眼
I was scolded by the teacher on the phone.
老師今天打電話來我就站在這裏給他罵耶
I...
我
- Hello? - This is Truly's cram school.
- 喂 - 我是林真心的補習班
Lin Truly is busy now.
林真心沒空啦
Hey...
欵
It's a guy...
男生耶
Hello?
喂
It's you again!
又是你
Never call again!
以後不準打電話來
You are so rude.
你這個人怎麼那麼沒有教養啊
If he calls again, let me pick it up.
如果再打來我接
Must be him.
一定是他
Pretending to be cram school staff.
裝補習班
Lin Truly.
林真心
Don't call me these two days.
這兩天你先不要打電話過來
What's wrong?
怎麼了
What happened?
發生什麼事
Nothing's wrong. Bye.
我沒事 先這樣
Are you ok?
沒事吧
It's so late... you must be going to bed?
這麼晚 你應該要睡了吧
I'm just stopping by.
我只是剛好經過
Well...
那
I'm leaving then.
我走羅
Hold on.
你等一下
ND.
瓦仔
Are you alright?
你還好嗎
Never knew I can be suspended from school.
第一次知道可以被禁學不用上課
Feels awesome.
超爽
I mean... you passed out at school...
我是說 那天在學校昏倒
It's just heat stroke.
中暑而已啊
Nothing fatal.
又不會死
Why are you suddenly grounded?
你怎麼突然被禁足
Anyone can be grounded for knowing you, ok?
任何人被發現認識你都會被禁足 好嗎
What brought you here?
你怎麼會來啊
Because you said...
因爲你說過
When a girl says "I'm ok", she's not ok.
女生說沒關係就是有關係
Nothing's wrong means something's wrong.
我沒事 就是有事啊
Do you want to come to a place with me?
要不要去一個地方
What?
蛤
Wait here.
你在這裏等我一下
Since I discovered this place,
我發現這裏以後
I've been coming here at midnight a lot.
就常常半夜來溜
You want to learn roller skating, right?
你不是想學溜冰
Let me tell you how not to fall.
告訴你不要摔倒的祕訣是什麼
What's the tip?
是什麼
Don't...
就是
be afraid of falling.
不要怕摔倒
It can't get worse than falling.
最慘就是摔倒而已
The important thing is...
重要的是
why are you here.
你爲什麼來這裏
Thank you.
謝謝
What?
幹嘛
On the day of school festival,
趁着校慶
let's give out awards to the top 10 students
現在我們來表揚
of the mock exam of 3rd grade.
三年級這一次模擬考前十名的同學
1st place.
第一名
Class 301, Ouyang Extraordinary.
三年一班歐陽非凡
2nd place.
第二名
Class 301, Li Chiming.
三年一班李智明
3rd place.
第三名
Class 302, Yang Chiaying.
三年二班楊佳穎
4th place.
第四名
Class 303, Liao Chide.
三年三班廖志德
10th place.
第十名 · · ·
5th place. Class 304, Tao Minmin.
第五名 三年四班陶敏敏
6th place.
第六名
Class 301, Lin Bingsheng.
三年一班林秉盛
7th place.
第七名
Class 309, Chen Yuting.
三年九班陳鈺婷
8th place.
第八名
Class 306, Li Chengfu.
三年六班李城甫
It's coming...
來了 · · ·
9th place.
第九名
Class 303, Wang Aiwei.
三年三班王艾偉
Get ready. Get ready.
準備  準備
Up to the stage, now!
上臺  上臺
Please come up to the stage.
以上九位同學上臺領獎
You might be wondering...
你們可能覺得很奇怪
why there are only 9 of them.
爲什麼沒有第十名
Because...
因爲
the school denounces cheating in exams.
學校嚴厲譴責考試作弊的行爲
We human beings must have a sense of shame.
做人要有羞恥心
You should never think those sneaky,
不要以爲偷雞摸狗
shameful behavior of yours
幹了不要臉的事情
will not be found out.
不會被發現
Hsu of Class 317, I'm talking about YOU.
三年十七班徐太宇我說的就是你
What rubbish?
胡說什麼
Mind your own business!
看什麼
Sir.
報告
We're giving out awards now,
這位同學
if you want to talk, we'll...
我們現在要頒獎 有什麼事情我們到 · · ·
Director.
主任
I have something serious to report now.
我有非常嚴重的事情必須立刻報告
My skirt is 3cm higher than my knee.
我的裙子比膝下短三公分
My socks are not 100% white.
襪子沒有全白
My jacket's zipper never pulled high enough.
外套拉鍊從來沒有拉到學號高度
Please punish me, sir.
請主任處份
All these are not important now.
現在這些不重要
We'll take our time to punish her later.
待會我們再來好好處罰這位同學
If none of these rules is important,
如果這些都不重要
why should we follow them?
我們爲什麼要遵守
Therefore,
所以
please cite me with an admonition
根據校規
according to school regulations.
請記我警告
Director.
報告主任
I cheated in exams.
我作弊
Please cite me with a major demerit
考試舞弊根據校規必須記大過
according to school regulations.
請主任處分
Ouyang.
歐陽同學
Don't play with your future.
不要拿自己的前途開玩笑
You're applying for Taiwan University,
尤其你申請臺大保送
Your discipline record can't be affected.
操行不能受影響
Besides, we know very well. You're smart.
況且學校很清楚
It's not possible that you...
依你的實力不可能
Why not?
爲什麼不可能
If Director Chuan can say that Hsu Taiyu
如果全主任可以說三年十七班
of Class 317 cheated on the exam,
徐太宇同學作弊
I can say I did it.
我現在說有
And what I say counts.
那就是有
Alright.
好
Since Ouyang confessed his crime bravely,
既然歐陽同學有勇氣自首
I'll make sure he gets a major demerit.
那我絕對嚴格執行記過
Director Chuan...
主任
We need further discussion.
這事還要再討論
Principal, Ouyang just...
校長 歐陽同學他
Director.
報告主任
I'm in shorts while it's not a P.E. class.
我在非體育課的時候穿短褲
Please cite me with an admonition.
請記我警告
Director.
報告主任
You're my chocolate.
你是我的巧克力
I'm disrespectful to teachers.
我態度輕浮隨便
Please cite me with an admonition.
請記我警告
Director.
報告主任
I spread obscene ideas.
我傳播猥褻思想
Please cite me with a minor demerit.
請記我一支小過吧
Director.
報告主任
Eat shit!
你吃屎吧
Sorry I humiliated teachers.
對不起我侮辱師長
Please cite me with a major demerit.
請記我大過一支
Director.
報告主任
I... I have a girlfriend.
我 · · ·有女朋友
Bullshit.
屁啦
Director.
報告主任
I brought my pager to school.
我私帶BBCall到學校
Please cite me with an admonition.
請記我警告一支
Director.
報告主任
I didn't flush the toilet.
我上廁所沒沖水
Director.
報告主任
I'm not wearing underpants.
我沒穿內褲
I play Game Boy in class.
我上課打電動
I sleep in class...
我上課睡覺
I have a boyfriend...
我有男朋友
Director.
主任
You said students should be like students.
你說學生要有學生的樣子
But neither exams nor school regulations
但是分數和校規
can define us.
都不能定義我們
Those with good scores can make mistakes.
成績好的學生也會犯錯
Those who made a mistake can improve.
曾經犯錯的有一天也會變好
Whether we're good or bad is not up to you.
是好是壞不是你說了算
Only we know who we are.
只有我們自己知道我是誰
Only we can decide the way we are.
只有我們自己能決定自己的樣子
Alright. Alright.
好 好 好
Calm down everyone.
同學冷靜
Today is the 54th anniversary of our school.
今天是我們五十四週年校慶
First High is always a liberal school.
一高一直自詡是間自由開放的學校
I'm here to promise you that, we'll discuss,
校長在這邊承諾同學
improve ourselves and proceed accordingly.
會檢討改進做出相對的處理
The long-waited water balloon fight
那麼同學們期待已久的水球大戰
officially starts now.
現在正式開打
We didn't know until years later...
很多年以後我們才知道
the first person you throw your balloon at,
讓你第一個砸下水球的人
is not someone you dislike,
不是你討厭他
but someone you can't take your eyes off.
而是你的眼裏  只有他
Hey! You meant it.
喂 你很故意耶
That's not true.
沒有啊
Just to wait for Dahe and Small.
等一下大賀跟小隻嘛
Are you tired?
累不累
Just to keep your hands warm.
這樣手比較不會冷
I picked your key.
我鑰匙抽到你耶
We must be meant for each other, right?
我們是不是很有緣啊
Meant for hell.
緣你媽啦
You're going so slow on purpose...
你故意騎這麼慢
is it because you want us to be alone?
是不是爲了想要跟我獨處啊
Boss...
老大
Sakuraki... wait for me!
櫻木 等等我
Follow the beat!
不要搶拍
Truth or Dare.
真心話大冒險
Ouyang...
歐陽
Are you seeing someone?
你有沒有喜歡的人啊
Is she here?
在不在現場
Yes, she's here.
有 在現場
Wow! Mr. Straight-A confessed his love.
哇  模範生表白了
Boss, boss.
老大 · · ·
So... are you seeing someone? Is she here?
那 你有喜歡的人嗎
Is she here?
她在現場嗎
Yes, she's here.
有 她在現場
Who's that?
誰啊
Boss, tell me... please.
好想知道老大
Hurry up...
快點
Oh... Lin Truly.
哦 林真心
Are you seeing someone?
你有喜歡的人嗎
Is he here?
他在現場嗎
Hold on.
欵 等一下
Is this bottle...
這個瓶子
pointing closer to Tao Minmin?
是不是比較靠近陶敏敏啊
Boss.
老大 · · ·
Ask again. Ask again.
你再問一次 快點 · · ·
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏
Ask again. Ask again.
再問一次 · · ·
Minmin, Minmin.
敏敏 · · ·
Have you ever sent out chain letters?
你有寄過幸運信嗎
What the hell is that?
你問這什麼問題啊
Drink it.
自己喝啦
How did you know that Minmin sent me
你怎麼知道
the chain letter and reported me?
敏敏寄給我幸運信 還跟老師舉發我
Who knows that you're sending chain letters?
誰會知道班上有人在寫幸運信啊
Must be the person who sent it to you.
當然是一開始寫信給你的人
Tao Minmin received exactly the same letter
如果陶敏敏收到過跟自己一模一樣的信
she sent out. That's why she knows
她纔會知道
one of the classmates who received
一定她自己害的同學裏面
her letter sent it to the teacher.
有人把幸運信寄給老師
I guess you're the only one who knows.
我猜她五封信裏面
Wang Baidan among the 5 receivers.
只有你認識王白丹
I never thought
沒想到
she would do something like this.
她會做這種事
I thought she was perfect.
我還以爲她很完美
Now I think your personality is better.
我現在倒覺得她個性沒有你好
And if I look closely...
認真看
she's not that much prettier than you.
好像沒比你漂亮多少
Maybe just this much prettier.
大概只有漂亮這麼 多
Which university do you want to go to?
你大學想要考哪裏啊
Taiwan University, I guess.
臺大吧
And you?
你呢
Same for me.
我也想上臺大
But... I don't think I can get in.
可是 考不上吧
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
If...
如果
we end up going to different universities,
我們沒有考到同一個地方
can you promise me?
你可不可以答應我
That...
以後
you'll continue to study hard and graduate.
還是好好讀書 好好畢業
That you'll never fight again...
不要再打架
That you'll never...
不要
worry people who care about you.
讓在乎你的人擔心
Ok.
嗯
I promise you.
我答應你
What about you?
那你呢
Yes?
嗯
If I go to somewhere very far from you,
如果以後 我跟你念的學校離的很遠很遠
can you promise me?
你可不可以答應我
That sesame dressing and noodles
麻醬麪 麻醬跟面
will never be mixed together.
還是要分開
Not funny.
白癡
I'm serious.
我是說真的
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Shooting star!
有流星
Make a wish.
快許願
Chain letters can never bring good luck.
幸運信從來就不能帶來好運
But on that night,
但那個晚上
I felt...
我卻覺得
I found my luck.
我找到了我的幸運
Welcome to the.
歡迎收看
"Superstitious Show".
鬼話連篇
Mom! It's starting!
媽 開始了啦
Let's have a look at this weird picture.
好我們在來看一張奇怪的照片
A group of high school students went
哦這是上個月一羣高中生
camping last month and took this photo.
去山上露營拍到的哦
Let's hear what the expert has to say.
我們先來看看專家怎麼說
The student in the photo
照片中的男同學
became translucent.
出現了半透明的現象
If we look at the supernatural aspect of it,
我們從靈學的角度去研判
it's obvious that
明顯的呢感應到
this photo
這張照片
is full of supernatural energy.
充滿着靈異的能量
I suggest the student
我建議這位同學
visit temples guarding land and underworld
要去拜土地公和城隍爺
- to remove ill fortune. - Go home soon.
- 來消災祈福 - 早點回家
Take care.
小心安全
Thanks.
謝啦
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I finally...
終於
got you.
堵到你了厚
The bell has rung.
同學打鐘羅
Hand in your paper.
交卷
Sakuraki said that.
我聽櫻木說啊
Hsu hasn't come to school for a week.
徐太宇已經一個禮拜沒有來學校上課
He's even absent from the mock exam.
連模擬考他都缺考
Did you watch the TV show last week?
你們有沒有看上個禮拜的玫瑰之夜啊
Maybe something really happened to him?
他不會真的出什麼事了吧
I don't think so.
不會吧
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Why didn't you take the mock exam?
你爲什麼沒來學校模擬考
None of your business.
不關你的事
Why did you... fight again?
爲什麼 又打架
For no reason.
沒有爲什麼
They wanted to fight.
他們想打
So I fought with them.
我就陪他們打
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I don't want to talk to you anymore.
我再也不想理你了
When a girl says
當一個女生說
"nothing's wrong", something must be wrong.
我沒事就是有事
"I'm ok" means "I'm not ok."
沒關係就是有關係
We didn't know until
很久很久以後
long after that:
我們才知道
When a girl says.
當一個女生說
"I don't want to talk to you anymore."
她再也不理你
She doesn't really hate you.
不是真的討厭你
Instead she cares about you...
而是她很在乎你
very
非常
very much.
非常 在乎你
Happy birthday!
生日快樂
Thank you...
謝謝
This is...
這是
Boss brought it back himself.
是老大親手去搬的
We don't know what he's been busy with,
最近他不知道在忙什麼
but he still remembers your birthday.
但是他還是記得明天是你的生日哦
And this!
還有這個
Boss said that you shouldn't listen to it
老大特別交代
before the university entrance exam.
聯考過後才能夠聽
There must be something special in it.
一定有什麼Special的
When you see boss in school tomorrow,
明天去學校
don't forget to thank him.
記得好好跟老大說聲謝謝
Bye bye.
再見
Lin Truly.
林真心
Today's your birthday, let's go to...
今天是你生日我看我們放學去吃
Chicken House...
香雞城
Great! Hand-shredded chicken set for me.
好 · · ·我要吃那個手扒雞套餐
I'm gonna have two.
我要吃兩隻
Look! It's Hsu Taiyu.
是 317 的徐太宇耶
Who is he looking for?
他要找誰啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
Lin Truly...
哦 林真心哦
go go go.
趕快去
He came to see you, Lin Truly.
特地來班上找你哦 林真心
Happy birthday...
過生日哦
So romantic!
好浪漫喔
Last night...
昨天
Thank you.
謝謝
Oh. You're welcome.
哦 沒什麼
Did you like it?
那東西你喜歡嗎
Of course!
嗯  當然啊
Happy birthday.
生日快樂
What did you want to say?
啊 找我什麼事啊
Small and Meimei are waiting for me.
小隻她們還在等我
We're discussing where to go for dinner.
我們在討論晚上要去哪裏慶生
Do you want to join us?
你要一起來嗎
By the way.
啊  對了
Please write this for me.
這個畢業紀念冊你拿去寫
Make sure you...
要照
fill in your personal info
第一頁那樣
like the sample on page 1.
填完個人資料哦
What's wrong?
嗯
Taiyu...
太宇
Were you looking for me?
你剛到班上來找我
For what?
做什麼
Wait for me here.
你等我一下
So you came for Minmin?
你是來找敏敏的啊
You should've told me...
早說嘛
you came for Minmin to...
你找敏敏 · · ·
She told me she likes me.
她跟我告白
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
怎麼現在才告訴我
Hmmm... congratulations.
嗯 恭喜啊
What a surprise!
嚇我一跳
I even helped you chase her for so long.
虧我幫你追她追那麼久
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Finally.
修成正果
Thank you.
謝謝你
It'll definitely work out
你跟歐陽
between Ouyang and you.
一定也沒問題的
Good luck.
祝你好運
Thanks.
嗯
I'm... really happy for you.
我 真的很替你開心
It's pouring rain...
雨很大了耶
Goodbye.
再見
Come with us...
一起走啊
It's ok. Thanks.
不用啦 謝謝
Look! It says that
喂 大成報說啊
Andy Lau has a girlfriend!
劉德華現在有女朋友耶
What? It must be rumor.
蛤 這一定是假消息啦
Andy Lau will never get married.
劉德華是永遠不會結婚的
We all dreamed of marrying our idols,
就像我們都幻想能嫁給偶像
That must be a rumor.
假的啦假的啦
But in reality...
但現實是
Of course Andy Lau belongs to someone else.
劉德華終究是別人的
Same for our first love.
我們的初戀
Of course we can't beat girls like Minmin.
註定會輸給像陶敏敏那樣的女孩
Morning.
早
Don't cry.
不要難過啦
Morning.
早安
Going abroad as soon as he got you.
追到手就出國唸書
He was just fooling you.
根本在耍你啊
In the end...
果然哦
we shouldn't have trusted a freak who
要求麻醬跟面分開的怪咖
separates sesame dressing from noodles.
還是不能相信啦
I heard that Director Chuan
我聽說啊
caught him fighting with others
全主任抓到他在校外械鬥
and wanted to kick him out of the school.
要他退學
That's why his dad sent him abroad.
所以他爸才把他送出國
What? Really?
蛤 真的假的
Shhh...
欵 · · · 噓
Quiet. Here she comes.
不要說了 她來了
What are you talking about?
在聊什麼啊
We are here to study.
我們是來看書的
- Yes - Right.
- 嗯 -  對
Back then, there was no facebook.
在那個沒有臉書的年代
12,000km means
一萬二仟公里
parting for good.
就是永別的距離
But sometimes
只是有時候
there were some moments,
在某個瞬間
I felt he would appear
會覺得好像下一秒
the next second.
他就會出現
Are you ok?
沒事吧
Be careful.
小心點
This is the ultimate note.
大補帖給你
等你考完
Let's go roller skating
after you finish the exam.
我們去溜冰
Or...
還是
do you want to go to the movies?
你想看電影
Ah! Stephen Chow's ”Monkey King” is on again.
啊  周星馳那部西遊記上二輪了
I want to watch it again.
我想再看一次
Last time...
上次
I didn't quite get it.
好像看不太懂
Hsu Taiyu left.
徐太宇離開了
My life
我的生活
seemed to be back to the same old.
好像回到遇見他之前的原點
But I know
但我知道
because of him.
因爲他
I am...
我纔是
who I am now.
現在的我
(TO: LIN TRULY)
(林真心 收)
好
OK.
(YOU'RE PRETTY. CAN I BE YOUR FRIEND?)
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Finally done with the entrance exam.
考完聯考了
Thanks.
謝啦
I think...
這次
I did pretty well in math.
數學成績還不錯
Thanks for the ultimate note.
多虧你整理給我的大補帖
Did you...
那
listen to the tape?
你聽了嗎
The one Taiyu gave you.
太宇送你的那捲卡帶
I promised him
提醒你這個
to remind you of this.
也是我答應他的事
It's a shame that
只是很可惜
the ending
結局
isn't like what he thought.
不是他想的那樣
Hsu Taiyu! Shooting star!
徐太宇 有流星
Make a wish!
快許願
You know that I heard it, right?
你不會以爲我會裝沒聽到吧
The person you like...
你喜歡的人
is here.
在現場
In the beginning,
一開始
I thought whoever believed in chain letters
看到有人相信幸運信這種事
was either an idiot
我覺得他應該不是白癡
or an idiot.
就是弱智
But later I realized that
可是後來發現
she's simply a very kind person.
她只是一個很善良的人
To whoever received this:
收到這封信的人
I am really really sorry.
真的對不起
I was forced to send it...
其實 我也是逼不得已的
You might be hit by a car,
你可能會被車撞
get cancer...
得絕症
or... lose your family.
或 · · ·或家破人亡
But...
但
I'm sure you'll turn ill luck into good,
你一定會逢凶化吉
have a successful life,
一帆風順
become wealthy.
年年有餘
That's why I wanted to know her.
所以說要跟他做朋友
Let's be friends.
我們  交個朋友吧
I was serious.
我是認真的
What?
蛤
I thought chasing girls...
本來我覺得追女生
was that simple.
不就這麼一回事
Tao Minmin.
陶敏敏同學
Wanna be my gal?
要不要做我女朋友
Say yes! Say yes!
大嫂 · · ·
Later I realized...
後來才明白
if you really like someone...
如果你真的喜歡一個人
you might not even notice it.
是不知不覺
I was actually super nervous that day.
那一天我其實超緊張
I have to thank that car.
感謝那輛車
The moment I held her in my arm...
搭住她肩的那一刻
I realized that I never knew...
我第一次發現
my heart... can beat so fast.
心 可以跳這麼快
What... were you... talking about?
剛 敏敏找你幹嘛
I didn't want her to misunderstand.
怕她誤會所以不想說太多
But somehow...
但是不知道爲什麼
at the end of that day
那一天到最後
she didn't seem happy.
她好像不太開心
When you like someone
原來喜歡一個人
and see her walk to someone she likes,
當你看到她走向她喜歡的人
you'd suddenly realize that
才突然發現
you treat her badly just because
你對她很壞
you want to get a bit closer to her.
只是爲了想跟她更靠近一點
For me?
送我哦
You'll keep every word she said
她說的每一句話
in mind.
你都會放在心上
Nothing's wrong.
我沒事
Bye.
先這樣
When we say nothing's wrong...
我們說沒事
it means something's wrong.
就是有事
When we say it's ok,
沒關係
it means it's not ok.
就是有關係
Are you ok?
沒事吧
I didn't know that when I'm in love,
原來喜歡一個人
I actually have no courage to tell her.
會沒有勇氣告訴她
On that night,
那個晚上
I made a wish upon a shooting star.
我向流星許願
I wish I was also
希望她的願望裏
in her wish.
也有我
Even if I know it's someone else
即使我知道能讓她快樂的
who could make her happy...
是另一個人
Sometimes... she still pretends to be ok
她 有時候明明很難過
even when she feels very sad.
還會逞強說自己沒事
Spending 5 minutes deciding what to have,
早餐會猶豫五分鐘
before choosing the same old raddish cake.
但最後還是選擇蘿蔔糕
She doesn't watch where she's going.
她常常走路不看路
Please watch her at all times.
要記得 時刻看着她
Are you ok?
沒事吧
She wants to go to Taiwan University,
想考臺大
but she's really bad at math.
但是數學很差
She likes roller skating,
喜歡溜冰
loves Stephen Chow's films...
愛看周星馳
Let's go roller skating
等你考完試
after you finish the exam.
我們去溜冰
She...
她
likes you very much.
她很喜歡你
I didn't know that
我後來才知道
he disappeared for so long
他失蹤那麼久
was because he had a surgery.
是在醫院開刀
Do you see that?
看到沒有
You have a blood clot here.
腦膜下腔這邊有一點血塊
This is why you passed out when running.
這就是造成你跑步暈倒的原因
It might be caused by the car accident.
可能是之前車禍的後遺症
That sounds really bad!
這麼嚴重哦
Should've charged the driver more.
早知道跟撞我的人多收一點醫藥費
You really should.
你的確應該
You'll need a surgery
這要動刀
and stay in the hospital.
還要住院
Your family has to come to look after you.
通知一下你的家人來照顧你
He wanted me to keep the secret.
他希望我保密
I guess...
我想
he didn't want you to blame yourself.
他一定是擔心你 因爲那場車禍自責
His family told the school long time ago
他們家很早就跟學校聯絡
that they wanted to take him to the U.S..
要他移民美國
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇同學
I hope you can start over again
我希望你到美國之後
after arriving in the U.S..
能夠重新開始
Director.
主任
Thank you.
謝謝
Sakuraki said that.
我聽櫻木說啊
Hsu hasn't come to school for a week.
徐太宇已經一個禮拜沒有來學校上課了
He's even absent from the mock exam.
連模擬考他都缺考
Aren't you moving to the U.S. soon?
之後開完刀你不是要跟家人移民了嗎
Why are you still studying this?
還讀這些幹嘛什麼
Because...
因爲
I made a promise.
我答應了一個人
Can you...
你可不可以
be that Hsu Taiyu again?
做回徐太宇
Why did you... fight again?
爲什麼 又打架
For no reason.
沒有爲什麼
They wanted to fight.
他們想打
So I fought with them.
我就陪他們打
Sorry for coming here so late
不好意思這麼晚來買東西
and asking that standee for free.
還要求加送人型立牌
Sorry.
歹勢啊
Hsu Taiyu.
徐太宇
I finally
終於
got you.
堵到你了厚
It's Andy Lau!
劉德華耶
Don't you motherfucker dodge!
他媽的你還敢閃
You want me to invite your gal for tea?
不要逼我請你馬子喝茶
She always goes to
她放學
that teashop to study.
會去小歇看書嘛
Class...
三年
304...
四班
Lin... Tru... ly...
林 真 心
Don't you ever touch her!
你敢動她試看看
It depends on whether you're a good boy...
那要看你今天聽不聽話
whether you let me beat you... up...
讓我打得爽不爽啊
Lin Truly.
林真心
Now you're with the person you like, right?
你現在應該跟喜歡的人在一起了吧
I won Tao Minmin's heart.
我追到陶敏敏
You won Ouyang's.
你追到歐陽
We fulfilled the promise
完成
we made in the beginning.
我們一開始說好的約定
I guess...
我想
this is the only
這是我能爲你做的唯一
and the last thing I could do for you.
也是最後一件事情
Lin Truly.
林真心
Although you're short
雖然你又矮
and stupid.
又笨
And you even like someone else.
還喜歡別的男生
Even so...
即使這樣
I still...
我還是
like you a lot.
很喜歡你
Lin Truly.
林真心
If you already listened to the whole tape,
如果你聽完這卷錄音帶
just look up at the sky.
就擡頭看看天上
Then I will know
因爲那時候我會知道
I'm looking at the same starry sky
原來我喜歡的那個女孩
as the girl I like.
正在看一樣的星空
I Love You.
Aqui te amo（西班牙文：我愛你）
(THE PERSON I LIKE: HSU TAIYU)
(我喜歡的人是徐太宇)
You were always wondering...
你常常幻想
what your future would be like.
長大後的你會是怎麼樣的
Now... I can give you the answer.
現在 我可以告訴你了
Give me the salary
給我該給的薪水
and the holidays I deserve,
放我該放的假
or let me quit.
不然你讓我辭職吧
I don't need to waste my life
人不需要在一個 不在乎你是誰的地方
in a place where no one cares who I am.
浪費自己的人生
Truly! Truly!
真心姐 · · ·
What the fuck!
哇靠
Handwritten resignation letter... so ancient.
這年代還有人手寫辭職信啊
We'd probably just send emails.
我們頂多發發mail
Who dares to
哪敢
do this.
這樣啊
You're so cool.
你太棒了
Sometimes...
有些事
it's still way cooler to
還是用我們的方式
do it our way.
比較屌
By the way.
還有
All of you have a share
我的業績獎金
of my performance bonus.
你們通通都有份
Yay!
呀
So you quit?
所以你辭職了
How can you be so immature?
你怎麼會這麼不成熟啊
Why can't you just be flexible?
爲什麼不懂得變通一下
Everyone can stick to it, why can't you?
大家都能繼續做下去爲什麼只有你不行
Do you remember that
你還記不記得有一次
once I asked you to pay card bill for me?
我叫你去幫我繳信用卡費
It's true I gave you the bill quite late.
我是很晚纔給你帳單沒錯
But it doesn't mean you could...
但是這也不代表你可以 · · ·
In the future...
長大後
you won't really become someone amazing.
你沒變得多了不起
You still make mistakes.
還是會犯錯
You still get confused.
還是會迷惘
You still regret for not having more ice,
會後悔沒多吃一點冰淇淋
or not experiencing more relationships.
多談幾次戀愛
That's what I don't like about you.
我已經說過好幾次我就是討厭你這樣
Same here.
我也討厭你這樣
Let's break up.
我們分手吧
And being too kind to people you dislike.
後悔沒對討厭的人更壞一點
And cherishing people you like more.
對喜歡的人更珍惜
But...
但是
the way you are is good.
這樣的你也很好
You're still very brave,
還是很敢
very naive.
還是很天真
You still...
還是
scream for your idol.
會爲了偶像尖叫
Ah!
啊
How can you stay so popular for 30 years?
爲什麼你紅了三十年還沒有過氣
How come I still can't get a single ticket!
爲什麼三十年後我還是買不到你的票
Come on. Come on.
快快快
Truly glow stick!
真心螢光棒
See, I finally got the ticket.
你看我終於買到票了
Where?
哪裏
I've queued for a long time!
排超久的你知道嗎
I'm in the first row at the mosh pit.
我的是搖滾區那一排
Come on. Come on. Have a look.
快看 快看  參考一下啦 · · ·
Truly glow stick!
真心螢光棒
Come have a look.
參考一下
Hello.
歡迎光臨小姐您好
May I help you?
想要喝什麼呢
Kumquat lemonade, please.
我要一個金桔檸檬
No problem.
好的沒有問題
30 dollars.
三十塊
Hello.
你好歡迎光臨
Bubble milk tea.
珍奶
Bubble milk tea? Sure.
珍奶嗎 好 沒問題
It's gonna take some time.
飲料現做稍等哦
You dropped something.
你東西掉了
I'm taking a break.
我出來透透氣
Just treat me as an ordinary person.
你把我當作普通人就好了
Don't worry.
你放心
I think you're so ordinary.
我覺得你超普通的
I don't like you at all.
我一點都不喜歡你
I'm not your fan.
我更不是你的粉絲
This is... what my colleague...
這 · · ·個是我剛剛
helped me...
中午的時候
download earlier today.
我同事幫我下載的
So good.
唱得好好哦
I...don't know who's the singer...
也 · · ·不知道是誰唱的
I agree.
我也覺得
It's good.
蠻好聽的
Let me play another song.
我把它關掉換一個
Can I take a photo with you?
我 · · ·可不可以跟你拍個照
Although you think I'm ordinary,
雖然你覺得我很普通
and you're not my fan.
不是我的粉絲
Can we... take a photo?
我能 拍嗎
Yes...
可以 · · ·
Ok.
好
Sorry, I'm a bit...
對不起 我有點
nervous.
緊張
Good?
可以羅
Thanks.
謝謝
Ok.
好啦
By the way...
欵 · · ·
Can you sign for me?
可不可以麻煩幫我籤個名啊
Sure.
好啊  來
Thanks.
謝謝
Oh!
哦
Can you please write...
可不可以麻煩再幫我寫
To Lin Truly.
"To 林真心"
L.l.N.
雙木林
Truly as in "Truly Madly Deeply".
真心誠意的"真心"
Lin Truly.
"林真心"
You're going to the concert tonight,
那今天晚上你去看演唱會吧
right?
是吧
How do you know?
你怎麼知道
Because
沒有
my concert is called "Truly Love You".
我的演唱會叫"真心愛你"
So...
所以
you really have to go.
你怎麼樣也要去
But I couldn't get any ticket.
可是我買不到票
All your concerts
你演唱會的票
are sold out.
賣光了都爆滿
Call this person.
你打這個電話
He's our staff.
我工作人員
You have to come.
那一定要來哦
OK.
好
Thank you.
謝謝
Bye bye.
再見
Don't forget.
記得哦
Bye bye.
Bye Bye
Hello?
喂
Hi...
嗯那個你好
hmmm...
是
Andy Lau gave me this number.
Andy劉德華給我這個電話
I guess he told you about it, right?
他應該有交代你們吧
My name is.
我的名字叫做
Lin Truly.
林真心
Is sesame dressing...
麻醬麪
still separated from noodles?
麻醬跟面還是分開放嗎
The concert will start soon.
演唱會很快就開始了
Are you excited?
你們期待嗎
I am.
我很期待
Because one of my friends made his efforts
因爲我有一個朋友
to make the concert happen.
他很努力的去促成這一次的演唱會
He wanted to fulfill a promise he made
他想完成自己一個年輕的承諾
to his first love.
爲了他的初戀情人
I like their story very much.
我很喜歡他們的故事
I want to dedicate this concert
這一次的演唱會
to everyone who has truly loved someone.
也希望送給所有真心愛過的朋友
Thank you.
謝謝你們
Truly love you.
真心愛你
Is that you...
這名字
come up with this title?
是你取的哦
Otherwise?
不然咧
The concert is starting soon.
演唱會快要開始羅
But...
可是
I didn't get any ticket.
我沒有買到票
I'll ask...
我叫
Andy Lau
劉德華
to sing for you.
唱給你聽
Yeah right.
最好是啦
Sure.
好啊
It's been a long time.
好久不見
《失戀陣線聯盟》草蜢
她總是隻留下電話號碼
從不肯讓我送他回家
聽說你也曾經愛上過她
曾經也同樣無法自拔
你說你學不會假裝瀟灑
卻教我別太早放棄她
把過去全說成一段神話
然後笑彼此一樣地傻
我們這麼在乎她
卻被他全部抹煞
越疼她越傷心
永遠得不到回答
到底她怎麼想
應該繼續猜測嗎
還是說好全忘了吧
找一個承認失戀的方法
讓心情好好地放個假
當你我不小心又想起她
就在記憶裏劃一個 X
她總是隻留下電話號碼
從不肯讓我送他回家
聽說你也曾經愛上過她
曾經也同樣無法自拔
你說你學不會假裝瀟灑
卻教我別太早放棄她
把過去全說成一段神話
然後笑彼此一樣地傻
我們這麼在乎她
卻被他全部抹煞
越疼她越傷心
永遠得不到回答
到底她怎麼想
應該繼續猜測嗎
還是說好全忘了吧
找一個承認失戀的方法
讓心情好好地放個假
當你我不小心又想起她
就在記憶裏劃一個